<source>
<publisher>Complete Staffing Jobs</publisher>
<publisherurl>https://completestaffingjobs.com</publisherurl>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2026 16:28:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<job>
<title>
<![CDATA[ Tool Design Manufacturing Engineer ]]>
</title>
<date>
<![CDATA[ Wed, 04 Mar 2026 16:28:12 +0000 ]]>
</date>
<expirationDate>
<![CDATA[ 2026-04-01 ]]>
</expirationDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p> <span><span><span><span>The Tool Design Manufacturing Engineer (TDME) is responsible for designing, developing, and improving tooling, fixtures, jigs, and dies used in metal stamping/progressive / compound die and other manufacturing machining operations (welding, work holding for tool room CNCs, and press brakes). This role works closely with production, quality, and tool room personnel to ensure tooling meets performance, safety, cost, and delivery requirements while supporting continuous improvement initiatives. The TDME interacts with the costing engineer by providing tool layouts and designs needed for the quoting process of new parts. Additionally, there is strong collaboration and team work with the rest of the engineering department where tool designs are reviewed and assistance is problem solving is obtained.</span></span></span></span></p> <p><span><span><strong><span><span><span>Essential Duties and Responsibilities</span></span></span></strong></span></span></p> <ul> <li><span><span><span><span>Designs tooling to produce parts using CAD (Solid Works, Logo Press &/or CADKEY) to customer specifications under instruction to ascertain specifications and objectives, nature of technical problem, and possible solutions such as part redesign, substitution of material or parts, or rearrangement of parts and subassemblies.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Collaborates with Tool Room, Maintenance, & Production to implement improvements for employee safety, production quality, and overall process effectiveness utilizing continuous improvement techniques.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Drafts detail drawings for fabrication by Tool Room.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Develop purchasing specifications for component parts.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Requisitions tools, equipment, and supplies.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Participation in internal and customer product and print design reviews</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Tool design for sheet metal punching, forming and fabricating</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Supports Tool Room & Production to troubleshoot tooling issues.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Identifies process improvement opportunities.</span></span></span></span> </ul> <p><span><span><span><span>Support new product introductions by designing and validating required tooling.</span></span></span></span></p> <ul> <li><span><span><span><span>Oversee tooling modifications, repairs, and improvements to enhance performance and tool life.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Work with tool room machinists to ensure designs are manufacturable and meet shop capabilities.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Conduct design reviews and ensure compliance with engineering standards and safety requirements.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Support continuous improvement, cost reduction, and cycle time optimization initiatives.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Maintain accurate documentation, revision control, and tooling records.</span></span></span></span> </ul> <p><span><span><span><span>? Applies technical knowledge to analyze, investigate and resolve assigned engineering problems.</span></span></span></span><br /> <span><span><span><span>? Design and implement manufacturing processes including production flow, machine operation methods and production equipment to support operators and drive process improvement.</span></span></span></span><br /> <span><span><span><span>? Create and modify work instructions as necessary to document processes critical to operations and quality establishing appropriate process controls.</span></span></span></span></p> <p><span><span><strong><span><span><span>Qualifications</span></span></span></strong></span></span></p> <ul> <li><span><span><span><span>Bachelor’s degree in Mechanical Engineering, Manufacturing Engineering, or related field (or equivalent experience).</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>3+ years of experience in tooling design within a manufacturing environment.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Strong proficiency in CAD software (e.g., SolidWorks, AutoCAD, or similar).</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Experience with fixtures, jigs, dies, and production tooling.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Strong problem-solving and analytical skills.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Ability to work cross-functionally and communicate effectively with shop floor personnel.</span></span></span></span> </ul> <p><span><span><strong><span><span><span>Preferred Qualifications</span></span></span></strong></span></span></p> <ul> <li><span><span><span><span>Experience in a precision machining or metal fabrication environment.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Familiarity with SPC, lean manufacturing, and continuous improvement methodologies.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Experience supporting ISO or quality management systems.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Hands-on tool room or machining background.</span></span></span></span> </ul> ]]>
</description>
<referencenumber>
<![CDATA[ 34707 ]]>
</referencenumber>
<url>
<![CDATA[ https://completestaffingjobs.com/jobs/tool-design-manufacturing-engineer-34707/?utm_source=indeed&utm_medium=Feed&utm_campaign=Aggregator ]]>
</url>
<company>
<![CDATA[ Complete Staffing Jobs ]]>
</company>
<streetaddress>
<![CDATA[ 677 Cambridge Street ]]>
</streetaddress>
<city>
<![CDATA[ WORCESTER ]]>
</city>
<state>
<![CDATA[ Massachusetts ]]>
</state>
<postalcode>
<![CDATA[ 01610 ]]>
</postalcode>
<country>
<![CDATA[ United States ]]>
</country>
<jobtype>
<![CDATA[ FULL_TIME ]]>
</jobtype>
<salary>
<![CDATA[ $100,000 ]]>
</salary>
<category>
<![CDATA[ Operations ]]>
</category>
<firstname>
<![CDATA[ Lewis ]]>
</firstname>
<lastname>
<![CDATA[ Simon ]]>
</lastname>
<applyEmail>
<![CDATA[ lsimon@completestaffingsolutions.com ]]>
</applyEmail>
</job>
<job>
<title>
<![CDATA[ Quality Supervisor ]]>
</title>
<date>
<![CDATA[ Wed, 04 Mar 2026 16:24:29 +0000 ]]>
</date>
<expirationDate>
<![CDATA[ 2026-04-01 ]]>
</expirationDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[ <p> <span><span><span><span>The Quality Supervisor is responsible for maintaining, implementing, and continuously improving the Quality Management System. <strong><em>This role emphasizes hands-on application of quality tools, development and delivery of training, and facilitation of systems that build organizational knowledge while driving measurable improvements in processes, products, and performance.</em></strong></span></span></span></span><br /> <span><span><span><span>The Quality Supervisor facilitates SPC and Gage R&R programs, serves as the Corrective Action Request (CAR) system coordinator, and supports managers with root cause analysis and corrective/preventive action development.</span></span></span></span></p> <div> <hr> </div> <h3><span><span><span><strong><span><span><span><span>Essential Responsibilities</span></span></span></span></strong></span></span></span></h3> <ul> <li><span><span><span><span>Drive continuous improvement through execution of improvement activities such as PIT teams, capability studies, SPC, and Gage R&R.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Serve as backup ISO/QS Management Representative for the QA Manager.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Develop and conduct training programs to establish a common understanding of quality tools, techniques, and best practices.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Maintain and monitor the corrective and preventive action (CAPA) process; serve as the primary customer QA contact for problem resolution.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Participate as a member of the APQP team, applying and teaching TQM tools in pre-production and improving APQP effectiveness.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Serve as a team leader, member, and/or advisor on Process Improvement and CAR teams, using hands-on opportunities to resolve issues while transferring knowledge to others.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Monitor and maintain the Gage R&R process; foster understanding through hands-on execution of studies and ensure system effectiveness.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Facilitate SPC processes; promote effective statistical analysis for product and process monitoring.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Establish and maintain systems for tracking CPK data and using it to drive internal improvements.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Promote data-driven decision-making by working with departments to appropriately use quality metrics.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Maintain current knowledge of quality concepts through seminars, literature review, and ongoing education; educate management and employees on quality tools.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Provide input into qualification of new equipment and processes.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Serve as backup support for QA staff and provide guidance in the absence of the QA Manager.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Complete additional tasks and special projects as assigned by the QA Manager.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Proactively identify issues and recommend solutions to reduce cost and improve performance.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Contribute to environmental objectives, targets, and programs in support of the Environmental Management System.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Ensure compliance with all company policies, procedures, safety rules, and regulations.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Minimize waste and conserve energy through reuse, recycling, and adherence to Environmental Management System practices.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Perform other duties within the scope of the position as required.</span></span></span></span> </ul> <div> <hr> </div> <h3><span><span><span><strong><span><span><span><span>Education and Experience</span></span></span></span></strong></span></span></span></h3> <ul> <li><span><span><span><span>Minimum 3–5 years of quality experience in a manufacturing environment required.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Minimum 7 years of experience in a manufacturing environment required.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Strong knowledge of ISO 9001 and AS9100 quality system requirements.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Working knowledge of ISO 9000 Quality System standards.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Understanding of total quality philosophies, principles, and objectives.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Mechanical or technical manufacturing experience preferred.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Laboratory experience, including metallurgical knowledge, preferred.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>SQE, ASP, or ASME certification preferred.</span></span></span></span> </ul> <div> <hr> </div> <h3><span><span><span><strong><span><span><span><span>Skills and Competencies</span></span></span></span></strong></span></span></span></h3> <ul> <li><span><span><span><span>Strong analytical, organizational, and problem-solving skills.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Excellent verbal and written communication skills.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Solid project management capabilities.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Ability to communicate effectively at all levels of the organization, from shop floor to senior management.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Working knowledge of human relations, group dynamics, and structured problem-solving techniques.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>High degree of initiative, creativity, and collaboration.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Ability to understand and follow quality and operational procedures.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Flexible and adaptable to changing business needs.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Capable of handling materials weighing over 40 lbs.</span></span></span></span> <li><span><span><span><span>Able to recognize and report errors in routing, prints, drawings, specifications, and materials.</span></span></span></span> </ul> <p> </p> ]]>
</description>
<referencenumber>
<![CDATA[ 34706 ]]>
</referencenumber>
<url>
<![CDATA[ https://completestaffingjobs.com/jobs/quality-supervisor-34706/?utm_source=indeed&utm_medium=Feed&utm_campaign=Aggregator ]]>
</url>
<company>
<![CDATA[ Complete Staffing Jobs ]]>
</company>
<streetaddress>
<![CDATA[ 677 Cambridge Street ]]>
</streetaddress>
<city>
<![CDATA[ WORCESTER ]]>
</city>
<state>
<![CDATA[ Massachusetts ]]>
</state>
<postalcode>
<![CDATA[ 01610 ]]>
</postalcode>
<country>
<![CDATA[ United States ]]>
</country>
<jobtype>
<![CDATA[ FULL_TIME ]]>
</jobtype>
<salary>
<![CDATA[ $80,000 ]]>
</salary>
<category>
<![CDATA[ Operations ]]>
</category>
<firstname>
<![CDATA[ Lewis ]]>
</firstname>
<lastname>
<![CDATA[ Simon ]]>
</lastname>
<applyEmail>
<![CDATA[ lsimon@completestaffingsolutions.com ]]>
</applyEmail>
</job>
</source>